A Guide to the Executive Papers of Governor Benjamin Harrison, 1781-1784
Library of Virginia
- Executive Papers of Governor Benjamin Harrison, 1781-1784., Extent: 19 boxes. (Box 1-19)
  Significant correspondents from Virginia State government include Governor Benjamin Harrison; William Davies, War Office; Edmond Randolph, Attorney General; William Rose, Keeper of the Public Jail; John Beckley, Clerk of the House of Delegates; and William Drew, Clerk of the Senate.
  Drafts of Governor Benjamin Harrison's correspondence can often be found among his Executive Papers. Harrison writes to William Davies regarding provisions to be supplied by Wills Cowper to the post at Portsmouth (1782 Mar. 22). Harrison also writes Joseph Holmes appointing him as district commissioner for the counties of Shenandoah, Frederick, Berkeley, and Hampshire (1782 Mar. 27). Finally, Harrison writes to the Chiefs, Headmen, & Warriors of the Cherokees regarding peace (1782 [N.D.]).
  William Davies served as commissioner of the War Office. William Davies writes regarding directions for the issuing of clothing to the artificers (1781 Dec. 8); canoes at Point of Fork & Westham (1781 Dec. 12); the sale of corn to the French (1781 Dec. 14); the refusal of 18-month men in Rockingham County to leave the county unless they receive their bounty (1781 Dec. 17); forage in the adjoining counties to the Albemarle Barracks (1781 Dec. 17); the contract of [Edward] Simpson of Fredericksburg with David Ross for making cartridge boxes (1781 Dec. 19); food for the troops at Cumberland Old Courthouse (1782 Jan. 11); the reorganization of several units and rations needed at several posts (1782 Jan. 15); the need for saddles & other equipment for the state cavalry (1782 Jan. 19); letter of Col. Simmonds of Charleston regarding the settlement of his claim against the state for supplies furnished the prisoners of war (1782 Jan. 23); the allowance made for the Commissary General of Stores (1782 Jan. 23); cannon in the Pamunkey River brought up from York & Cumberland (1782 Feb. 25); subscription papers for the relief of officers & soldiers (1782 Feb. 28); Gen. Clark's letter requesting to be joined by Col. Charles Dabney's Legion and the need for cannon (1782 Mar. 23); cannon at Manchester for Gen. Clark (1782 Mar. 25); boats to be supplied by Maj. Harding on the Ohio for Gen. Clark (1782 Apr. 22); Arthur Campbell's letter proposing that the commanding officers of Montgomery & Washington order out their militia to protect against the Northern Indians (1782 June 6); artificers at the Point of Fork & the appointment of a person to take charge (1782 July 17); a list of staff within the War Dept., their pay, rank, rations, etc. (1782 July 30); and collecting clothing, payment for his servant acting as doorkeeper, the delivery of his papers of the War Office, & the settling of his accounts as he leaves office (1782 Dec. 9).
  Edmund Randolph, Virginia's first Attorney General, provides the governor with several opinions on issues affecting the Commonwealth. On 4 April 1782, Randolph states that an examination & acquittal before a single magistrate is not a bar to a second prosecution (1782 Apr. 4). In addition, Randolph provides his opinion based on the petition of Mace Freeland for the division of the escheated estate of his nephew, Robert Williams (1782 Apr. 8). His letter of 12 May 1782 relates to criminals convicted of horse stealing. Additional opinions were provided by Randolph on the following subjects: the governor's power to grant reprieves or pardons (1782 June 15); the transport of enemies as passengers on board vessels sent with a flag to New York (1782 Aug. 5); five suits in which La Croix, a French subject, is plaintiff and some of the justices of Accomack County, defendants, in the General Court (1782 Aug. 9); attacks on flags of truce (1782 Aug. 13); the suit in the General Court on behalf of Thomas Brown against Robert McLanahan (1782 Aug. 27); recommending the pardon of Elkanah Hudson in order to become a witness against two men accused of horse stealing (1782 Dec. 10); the claim of Simon Nathan arbitrated by him with the Commonwealth at Baltimore (1783 Aug. 20); the demand on Virginia by South Carolina for George Hancock, a citizen of Virginia, charged with high misdemeanor (1784 Jan. 21); the recovery of damages by civil suit, or the offenders by indictment for the persons aggrieved by the outrage of the Irish vessel (1784 Oct. 13); the filling of vacancies in the Court of Kentucky (1784 Oct. 19); and the case of the will of Maj. Gen. Charles Lee who made his sister Sidney Lee his legatee (1784 Nov. 23).
  Keeper of the Public Jail, William Rose, provides the governor with information on the jail. On 31 December 1781, Rose encloses a narrative by Jackson, a prisoner in the Public Jail, regarding the escape of a company of bandits in North Carolina composed of horse thieves, counterfeiters, and others. Rose also encloses a list of criminals tried, convicted, & condemned at December General Court. Additionally, Rose writes requesting clemency on behalf of one Robert Hudgins (1782 Nov. 20). Rose encloses a descriptive list of the criminals conditionally pardoned on 26 November 1782. In April 1783, Rose submits a calendar of prisoners in the Public Jail. Rose applies to the judges of the General Court for proper regulations for the government of the Public Jail and requests a tolerable habitation for himself and his family where the old prison stands (1783 Apr. 24). Additional correspondence from Rose relate to the following: the deplorable condition of the Public Jail, the use of slaves for the jail, & the need for a pump & oven in the jail (1783 July 2); the resolution of the Assembly empowering the Executive to direct the building of a brick wall around the new prison (1783 July 6); the state of the Public Jail (1783 Oct. 28); and his necessity for new housing & the removal of the guards at the Public Jail (1784 Apr. 30).
  As clerks of the House of Delegates and Senate, John Beckley and William Drew often transmitted various resolutions & acts to Governor Harrison. Noteworthy legislation include the following: resolution that the proposed expedition against Detroit not be attempted and that some plan of defense be adopted for the security of the inhabitants residing in the western frontier (1781 Dec. 11); resolution in favor of the memorial of Daniel Clarke praying that the conditional acceptance of David Ross, Commercial Agent, of a bill of exchange drawn by Oliver Pollock at New Orleans (1781 Dec. 25); resolution that the governor & council lay before the General Assembly a state of the Illinois Department (1782 June 14); resolution that the governor give necessary assistance for carrying the views of Congress & their financier into due effect respecting the loading & clearing the vessels with tobacco (1782 June 15); resolution that the governor & Council be empowered to appoint one or more persons to provide quarters, boats, & other necessaries for the use of the French Army (1782 July 1); act to repeal the several acts of Assembly respecting the Commissioner of the War Office & Commercial Agent (1782 Oct. 21); resolution that all officers & soldiers who have been taken by the enemy have their accounts of pay settled & adjusted (1782 Nov. 30); resolution that the Executive be authorized to restore to the respective proprietors any slaves now at the lead mines (1782 Dec. 6); resolution that the governor be requested to lay before the House a state of the monies received agreeable to an act entitled an act to recruit the state's quota of troops to serve in the Continental Army (1783 May 19); resolution for a statue to be erected as a monument of affection & gratitude to George Washington (1784 June 22); resolution for a return of all officers of the State Line & Navy be made to the next General Assembly (1784 June 29); resolution for the free navigation of the Mississippi River (1784 Nov. 3); resolution for the encouragement of treating with the Indians with commissioners of Congress (1784 Nov. 5); and a resolution that the Executive be requested to cause copies of the Articles of Confederation, Declaration of Rights, & Virginia Constitution to be distributed to the counties (1784 Nov. 27).
  John Beckley & William Drew also provide the governor with extracts of the journal and certificates of election of the Senate & House of Delegates regarding the election various individuals to public office. Included are the following: John Marshall to the Privy Council (1782 Nov. 20), Benjamin Harrison as governor (1782 Nov. 20 & 1783 Nov. 27); William Short to the Privy Council (1783 June 10); William Christian & William Nelson, Jr., to the Privy Council (1783 Nov. 27); John Francis Mercer as a delegate in Congress (1784 June 28); James Wood & James McClurg to the Privy Council (1784 June 22); George Savage as naval officer for the Northampton District (1784 June 26); Joseph Jones to the Privy Council (1784 Nov. 19); and Spencer Roane & Miles Selden, Jr., to the Privy Council (1784 Nov. 19).
  Governors from other states comprise a significant amount of correspondence received by the governor. This correspondence mostly relates to fugitives, boundary lines, Indian affairs, mutineers, and other subjects. Included are letters from the following governors: Thomas Lee, Maryland; John Mathews & Benjamin Guerard, South Carolina; Alexander Martin, North Carolina; John Dickinson, President of Pennsylvania; and George Clinton, New York.
  Gov. Thomas Lee, Maryland, writes re. a line of posts from Alexandria through Maryland (1782 Jan. 2). Gov. Lee also encloses resolutions re. the conduct of the assessor of Baltimore in assessing two ships of war belonging to Virginia (1782 May 24). Gov. John Mathews, South Carolina, recommends an expedition against the Indians along the western frontiers of Georgia, South Carolina, North Carolina, & Virginia (1782 June 12). Mathews's successor, Benjamin Guerard, writes to demand George Hancock, guilty of high misdemeanor on the assault against Jonas Beard, a justice of the peace (1783 Dec. 16). Guerard also writes re. fugitives from justice (1784 Feb. 3). Finally, Guerard requests a list of persons who were banished from their perspective states (1783 Aug. 13). Gov. Alexander Martin, North Carolina, writes re. peace with the Chickasaw & Cherokee Indians (1782 Nov. 21). Martin also writes re. a treaty with the Cherokees & a commercial treaty between Great Britain & the U.S. (1783 July 12). Lastly, Martin writes re. a person in the Richmond Jail who is supposed to be one of the mutineers who murdered some of the officers of the privateer Gen. Gregory (1783 Aug. 20). John Dickinson, President of Pennsylvania, writes re. the defense of Pennsylvania against the complaints of Monongalia (1783 July 3). Dickinson encloses a resolution of the General Assembly of Pennsylvania re. the appointment of commissioners for running a line between Pennsylvania & Virginia (1783 Sept. 20). Dickinson also writes re. John Campbell's memorial respecting his claim to lands lying within the limits of Pennsylvania ceded by Virginia (1784 Feb. 4). Gov. George Clinton, N.Y., acknowledges receipt of acts of the Virginia legislature (1784 Apr. 20). Clinton also writes regarding the uneasiness expressed by Indian tribes as a result of the people of Virginia surveying & taking possession of lands west of the Ohio claimed by the Indians (1784 July 13).
  Miscellaneous correspondents to Governor Harrison include the Count de Rochambeau, Arthur Campbell, Joseph Martin, George Rogers Clark, and Nathanael Greene.
  Count de Rochambeau served as commander-in-chief of the French Expeditionary Force that came to the aid of America during the Revolution. Rochambeau writes to congratulate the governor on his election, his offer to receive Dudley Digges as agent for the state, & news of Admiral Robert Digby's fleet in New York (1781 Dec. 7); a chain of communication with Richmond & Maryland (1781 Dec. 21); his answer to the resolve of the Council of State accepting gratitude of the state for the role played by French forces in its defense (1782 Jan. 10); the march of the Legion de Lauzon once they receive provisions, the rumored arrival of additional English troops from Ireland, & the birth of the Dauphin (1782 Jan. 26); intelligence of privateers entering the Chesapeake Bay & communications with Gen. Greene (1782 Mar. 1); runaway slaves in the French Army belonging to Americans (1782 Mar. 10); the complaint from Charlotte Courthouse about the taking of a public granary for a hospital for the legion (1782 May 9); peace proposals from England, naval engagements at St. Thomas, & refugees in New York (1782 May 12); the enforcement of the trade terms of the Yorktown capitulation (1782 May 20); and the establishment of the militia in York & its environs under Gen. Edward Stevens & negroes belonging to French officers (1782 June 28).
  Arthur Campbell, a prominent frontiersman during the Revolutionary War, maintains regular correspondence with the governor from Washington County. Campbell writes regarding intelligence that a body of Indians & Tories are preparing to attack the frontier (1782 Jan. 3); the employment of part of the force of the Carolinas & Georgia against the unfriendly Southern Indians & Tories (1782 Mar. 13); attacks by the Indians (1782 Apr. 25); intelligence respecting the temper of the seceding Cherokees & the measures adopted in North Carolina to subdue them (incl. a letter from Joseph Martin, Agent of Indian Affairs) (1782 July 31); intelligence of the peaceable disposition of the seceding part of the Cherokee Indians (1782 Aug. 5); peace with the Cherokees (1782 Aug. 26); supplies sent to the Indians through Joseph Martin, negotiations with the Cherokees, & an attack near Abingdon (incl. letter of Joseph Martin) (1782 Sept. 20); war in the Kentucky country & the expedition of the Carolinas against the Cherokees (1782 Oct. 3); Indian attacks on Christmas Day and recommendations for a fort on Sandy River (1783 Jan. 29); the repulse of Indian attacks on the fort at Clinch Settlement (1783 Apr. 1); and a letter of Daniel Smith re. an account of an Indian incursion at the fort at Hamlin's Mill (1783 June 1)
  Col. Joseph Martin as Indian Agent for Virginia & North Carolina corresponds with Governor Harrison regarding Indian affairs, peace talks, & supplies. Some of this correspondence was sent to the governor in conjunction with Col. John Donelson as joint commissioners to treat with the Chickasaw Indians. Included are letters concerning the following subjects: assistance of clothing & ammunition for the Cherokees (1782 May 3); talks with the Cherokees, Chickasaws, Creeks, & Choctaws and a planned campaign with British forces against Ft. Pitt (1783 Feb. 2); a place for holding a treaty with the Chickasaw Nation, Indian attacks on the Clinch settlements, settlement incursions on Indian territory by North Carolina, & an expedition to raid Spanish boats on the Mississippi (1783 Apr. 14); treating with the Chickasaws, ammunition for the Cherokees, treaty with the Shawnee, & an attack upon the Spanish settlement at Ozark (1783 July 20); Indian affairs and a proposed place of meeting to form a treaty with the Chickasaws (1783 Aug. 30); Indian affairs and the encouragement of the Spaniards for the Indians to war against the states (1783 Sept. 27); propositions for peace with the Shawnee (1783 Oct. 18); negotiations with the Indians, the hostility of the Creeks, Spanish traders, & an express sent to the Shawnee (1783 Dec. 16); the purchase of land on the Tennessee River from the Cherokees, the expedition against the Chickamauga, & the condition of the Henry County (1784 Feb. 16); the condition of settlers, stolen horses, the death of the king of the Chickasaws, & Indian outrages (1784 July 22); and a letter from the Chickasaw Nation re. a council between the Chickasaws & Choctaws with the Spaniards (1784 Sept. 2).
  George Rogers Clark, distinguished Revolutionary War general, maintained a regular communication with Governor Harrison. Clark writes from Ft. Nelson regarding the enemy at Detroit, Indian attacks, & requests for reinforcements (1782 Mar. 7). Clark later writes from Lincoln County regarding the establishment of the post at Licking, the commencement of hostilities, & the need for flour (1782 Feb. 18). On 2 May 1782, he encloses a copy of his letter to Col. William Davies regarding alarming accounts from the enemy at Detroit. Additional correspondence from Clark relates to the following topics: the arrival of supplies, Col. Slaughter's Corps, the care of stores, the settlement of accounts, & plans for an expedition against the Shawnee (1782 Oct. 19 & 22); the expedition against the Shawnee (1782 Nov. 27); the construction of outlying posts & the slaughter at Blue Licks (1782 Nov. 30); the settlement of western accounts (1782 Dec. 15); the condition of his troops & forts in Kentucky (1783 Jan. 1); state of the garrison at Ft. Nelson, general return of the strength of the Illinois regiment, & proceedings of the Board of Officers of the Illinois Regiment at Ft. Nelson (1783 Feb. 25); state of the frontier & plan for its defense (1783 Feb. 25); contact with the Chickasaw Chiefs & the situation of the frontier (1783 Mar. 8); peace with the Indians, the establishment of a post at the mouth of Kentucky, & ammunition to be conveyed to Kentucky (1783 Apr. 30); the speech of the chiefs of the Oubash Indians, peace treaties with the Oubash & Chickasaws (incl. instructions to the county lieutenants of Jefferson & Lincoln) (1783 Apr. 30); a plan of offensive measures against the Indians (1783 May 22); and high prices in the western country (1783 June 26).
  Nathanael Greene, Major General of the Continental Army, writes concerning the state's plan to raise three thousand men, his disappointment that Virginia has departed from Congress's plan for obtaining a revenue tax for the support of the war, the Virginia Assembly's opposition to the plans of the Financier, and the maintaining of a garrison at York & Gloucester (1782 July 25). Greene later writes regarding Virginia's proposal to complete the Virginia State Line and a possibility that the enemy will evacuate the country (1782 Aug. 12). Greene writes regarding Virginia's cavalry, calling up troops for internal protection, appointments by Col. White, & the sending of troops back to Virginia (1782 Oct. 24). Greene also writes concerning the following subjects: the evacuation of Charleston (1782 Dec. 20); goods for the army purchased by Hunter, Banks & Co. (1782 Dec. 20); clothing for the army (1783 Feb. 3); and mutiny by the 1st Regiment of Virginia Cavalry and steps to bring them to punishment, especially their ringleader, Sgt. Dangerfield (1783 May 20 & 27).
  Additional significant correspondence includes: Col. Joseph Holmes, Richmond, re. his plan for providing a guard for the British prisoners at Winchester (1781 Dec. 13); Col. James Wood, Winchester, re. his appointment as Superintendent of the Prisoners of War in Virginia and the need for more provisions (1781 Dec. 27); Nathanael Greene, Headquarters, re. reinforcements from Virginia (1781 Dec. 28); Edward Carrington, Richmond, re. orders to keep a significant number of boats in readiness at Westham to remove the public stores at Manchester up the James River in case of the approach of the enemy (1782 Jan. 3); James Barron, Hampton, encl. dimensions of a galley to be built (1782 Mar. 1); Robert Andrews re. his compensation for a commission on the part of Virginia to run the boundary line between Virginia & Pennsylvania (1782 Mar. 9); Richard Kello resigning as judge of the Court of Admiralty (1782 Mar. 25); John Tyler, Charles City, re. recruiting soldiers for the Continental Army using part of the land tax collection (1782 Apr. 15); David Sprout, New York, Commissary General for Naval Prisoners, re. the exchange of naval prisoners at Philadelphia (1782 Apr. 22); William Hay, Commercial Agent, encl. an account of sundry goods delivered to Col. Joseph Martin, the Cherokee Indians, & their interpreter (1782 May 7); Thomas Meriwether requesting an appointment as second clerk to the executive (1782 May 7); James Barron, Hampton, encl. a resolution of the House of Commons re. the impracticality of the war against the colonies and that a bill for establishing a peace or truce with America (1782 May 15); William Hay accepting his appointment as Commercial Agent (1782 May 24); Guy Carleton, New York, re. the sloop William & John captured in Hampton (1782 July 7 & 26); Le Chevalier de Lavalette re. taking command of the French troops at York & West Point from Count de Rochambeau (1782 July 9); Chiefs of the Chickasaw Nation to the commanders of stations between the nation & the Falls of the Ohio re. their desire for peace (1782 July 9); Leighton Wood, Jr., Solicitor, re. his duty to prepare the accounts of the Commonwealth for a settlement (1782 July 18); Le Chevalier de Lavalette re. his orders from Count de Rochambeau to embark for Baltimore all the French artillery at West Point (1782 July 28); Capt. John Peyton accepting his appointment as superintendent of the Point of Fork (1782 Aug. 4); Guy Carleton, New York, re. conferences in Paris for a general peace (1782 Aug. 5); Thomas Jefferson, Monticello, encl. letters from Col. Thomas Turpin re. payment for the rent of his tenement in Richmond to the governor (1782 Aug. 7); Guy Carleton, New York, enclosing a copy of a pass given to Charles Godfrey, master of the sloop Dove, to proceed to the Chesapeake and an account of work done to the sloop (1782 Aug. 21); William Foushee, Mayor of Richmond, re. the establishment of a city watch, the expulsion of disorderly persons of a suspicious character, and the removal & change of the present guard at the Public Jail (1782 Aug. 29); Daniel Boone, Fayette County, re. an attack by Indians & white men on Bryan's station (includes list of casualties) (1782 Aug. 30); John Bowman, Lincoln, County, enclosing a talk from the Chickasaw Chiefs re. their willingness to treat with Virginia for peace (1782 Aug. 30); Col. Benjamin Logan, Lincoln County, providing an account of the disaster at Blue Lick (includes rough drawing of battlefield) (1782 Aug. 31); John Donelson, Lincoln County, encl. a talk from the Chickasaw Chiefs soliciting peace (1782 Sept. 1); Capt. John Peyton, Point of Fork, re. the exchange of certain articles suitable for soldiers' clothing & the removal of arms from Westham (1782 Sept. 3); Charles Dick, Fredericksburg, re. the return of arms repaired in August and requesting pay for the artificers (1782 Sept. 4); Jaquelin Ambler, Treasurer, encl. a list of tobacco & flour received by virtue of the act for ascertaining certain taxes & duties and for establishing a permanent revenue (1782 Sept. 6); Richard Henry Lee, Chantilly, re. recruiting the army in Westmoreland County (1782 Sept. 6); Harry Innes declining an appointment as assistant judge in the Kentucky District (1782 Sept. 9); Daniel Boone, Levi Todd, & others requesting 200 men and artillery for protection against further attacks by Indians (1782 Sept. 11); Charles Dick, Fredericksburg, re. the state of the Gun Factory in Fredericksburg (1782 Sept. 12); Guy Carleton re. suspension of hostilities (extract of letter) (1782 Sept. 12); George III to Richard Oswald, London, giving him power to negotiate peace with the U.S. (1782 Sept. 25); talk delivered by Old Tassell, a Cherokee Chief, to Col. Joseph Martin requesting supplies (1782 Sept. 25); William Hay, Commercial Agent, re. the purchasing of stores for the State Legion (1782 Oct. 9); Jaquelin Ambler, Treasurer, encl. a return of specifics received at the Treasury by virtue of the revenue law (1782 Oct. 16); S. Clark, Lincoln County, re. peace with the Chickasaws, the purchase of territory on the Tennessee River, & the hostile disposition of the Northwestern Indians (1782 Oct. 18); Chevalier D'Anmours, Consul General of France, Baltimore, re. the arrest of French deserters in Virginia (1782 Oct. 21); William Hay resigning as Commercial Agent (1782 Oct. 21); Leighton Wood, Solicitor, re. the enforcement of the act calling for the suspension of naval officers who do not submit accounts of monies received (1782 Oct. 21); Charles Dick, Fredericksburg, enclosing an estimate of the expenses of the Gun Factory for one year (1782 Oct. 24); Paul Carrington, B. Dandridge, Peter Lyons, & James Mercer encl. a list of criminals condemned at the last session of the General Court (1782 Nov. 1); Thomas Barclay, L'Orient, re. receipt of his appointment as agent at the Court of France for the State of Virginia (1782 Dec. 6); John Cropper, Jr. Accomack County, re. an engagement at Cagey's Straits (incl. list of wounded) (1782 Dec. 6); William Christian, Ft. Nelson, re. the deplorable condition of the Cherokees & measures for their relief (1782 Dec. 16); George Walls, Ft. Nelson, encl. a general return of the garrison at Ft. Nelson & an inventory of ordnance & military stores (1782 Dec. 16); William Fleming, Samuel McDowell, & Caleb Wallace, Lincoln Co., approving the erection of a fort at the mouth of Kentucky (1782 Dec. 23); William Christian, Mahanaim, requesting Sampson Matthews to remove Col. Joseph Martin, Virginia's Indian Agent, from his present location at "The Island" in North Carolina to the Cumberland Gap (inc. sketch of a map of Washington County) (1782 Dec. 30); Thomas Barclay, Commercial Agent for Virginia in France, re. France's unwillingness to make loans to individual states (1783 Jan. 5); Thomas Prosser & William Hay re. the pay of Col. Turpin for the rent of his house & garden for the governor (1783 Jan. 8); Oconostota, Kenitita, & the Old Tassell to Col. Joseph Martin re. goods & ammunition for the Cherokees (1783 Jan. 25); Thomas Barclay, L'Oreint, re. a letter of Dr. [Benjamin] Franklin concerning preliminary articles of peace between France, Spain, & Great Britain (incl. copies of the 1st & 22nd articles re. the restoration of prizes taken on the seas) (1783 Jan. 27); William Christian, Mahanaim, re. the removal of Col. Joseph Martin to Cumberland Gap, a post at the mouth of Licking River, & the vulnerability of Fayette County (1783 Jan. 29); Col. John Donelson, Long Island, re. his appointment to act as joint commissioner with Col. Joseph Martin to treat with the Southern Indians for peace (1783 Feb. 2); Paul Loyall, Thomas Brown, & Thomas Newton, Jr., Commissioners of the Navy, re. the defense of the Chesapeake Bay and encl. speech of the King of Great Britain (1783 Feb. 17); William Fleming, Samuel McDowell, & Caleb Wallace re. the settlement of Western accounts (1783 Feb. 17); Turner Southall re. his appointment as builder & superintendent of the Foundry (1783 Feb. 21); Guy Carleton, New York, re. the quantity & value of wine on board the sloop William & John taken off Hampton roads (1783 Mar. 9); Paul Loyall, Thomas Brown, & Thomas Newton, Jr., Naval Commissioners, Norfolk, re. armed vessels to protect trade (1783 Mar. 12); Joseph Nevill, Hampshire, encl. an account of expenses for running the temporary boundary line between Virginia & Pennsylvania (1783 Mar. 19); Leighton Wood, Treasurer, encl. a list of judgments against delinquent sheriffs obtained by him at the last General Court (1783 Apr. 28); John Beckley, clerk of the Court of Appeals, re. the law books collection & care at public expense (incl. letter of Edmund Randolph re. the state of the books) (1783 Apr. 30); John Peyton, Commissary of Public Stores, encl. an estimate of expenses per annum of the Commissary of Military Stores Department (1783 May 17); John Dodge, Kaskaskia, to the King of the Chickasaw Nation re. the capture of Detroit & the withdrawal of the British (1783 June 23); Thomas Jefferson to Edmund Randolph re. the case of Simon Nathan for bills drawn by Gen. Clark & others (1783 July 18); James Colbert, Chickasaw Nation, re. relations between the Americans & Chickasaws (incl. letter of the Chickasaws) (1783 July 25); Edmund Pendleton, Caroline, re. the collecting & preserving of the laws (1783 July 29); Caleb Wallace, Botetourt County, resigning as one of the assistant judges of the Supreme Court for the District of Kentucky (1783 Aug. 14); Maj. George Walls re. incursions by the Shawnee, the return of prisoners, & problems with the Cherokees (1783 Sept. 11); Zephaniah Turner encl. his qualification as commissioner of accounts of the State of Virginia (1783 Sept. 24); Robert Andrews, Williamsburg, accepting his appointment as one of the commissioners to run the line between Virginia & Pennsylvania (1783 Oct. 20); George Walls re. peace with the Shawnee (1783 Oct. 26); John Page, Roswell, accepting an appointment to run the line between Virginia & Pennsylvania (1783 Oct. 27); Caburrus, Vice Consul of France, re. a difficulty between a French captain & two American sailors (1783 Nov. 12); Thomas Lewis, Rockingham County, acknowledging his declining the appointment as one of the commissioners to run the boundary line between Virginia & Pennsylvania (1783 Nov. 29); Col. Isaac Shelby, Lincoln co., re. the treaty with the Chickasaws (1783 Dec. 1); James Madison, Robert Andrews, & John Page re. expenses in running the boundary line between Pennsylvania & Virginia (1783 Dec. 2); John Page, Williamsburg, providing further particulars in the expenses of the commissioners for running the boundary line between Pennsylvania & Virginia (1783 Dec. 2); Dudley Digges, President of the Board of Directors, encl. proceedings of the Court of Directors of the Public Hospital for Lunatics, re. an order on the Auditor in favor of James Galt, later keeper (1784 Feb. 3); Chiefs & Brothers of the Shawnee Nation re. peace between the Shawnee & Americans (1784 Feb. 7); Samuel Patteson resigning as assistant clerk of the Council (1784 Apr. 5); Levi Todd, Fayette County, re. hostilities with the Indians in Kentucky and a lack of authority to call out troops (1784 Apr. 15); David McClure, Clerk of Ohio County, re. the destitute situation of Yohogania County within Virginia (1784 May 2); Walker Daniel, Lincoln, Kentucky, re. the state of Indian affairs and actions against Pomeroy & others for sedition (1784 May 21); B. Johnston, Yohogania County Surveyor's Office, encl. a list of entries for lands within the bounds of the cession to Pennsylvania (1784 June 29); Samuel Hawes & Thomas Meriwether accepting the appointment as commissioners to examine into all impositions in the settlement of the officers & soldiers accounts (1784 July 2); Jaquelin Ambler, Treasurer, informing the governor that there is no money in the Treasury and encl. a resolution that the treasurer pay out of the money arising under the law for recruiting 